Alex Deryugin

Beverly Hills, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Alex-Deryugin/fa87f9c3af28f847

Over 10 years of Java Enterprise programming

Exceptional record overseeing all facets of Software Development Life Cycle, from analysis and design to implementation and maintenance

RESTful Java Web Services

Strong Programming Skills in designing and implementation of multi-tier applications using Java, J2EE, JDBC, JSP, HTML, JSF, JavaScript, Servlets, JavaBeans, CSS, EJB

Experience in Java design patterns such as Session Façade, Singleton, Data Access Objects (DAO), and Business Delegate.

Developled N-Tier architecture systems using Java, Spring and Hibernate

Developing and running Java Web and Enterprise apps on variety of app servers

Expertise with web based GUI architecture and development using JavaScript, JSP, PrimeFaces

Database development in MySQL.

Strong troubleshooting and problem-solving skills.

Experience using various UML diagrams for design and architecture

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

- September 2009 to Present

09/2009 - current

Developing high volume workflow software suit using Java, Tomcat 7, Jboss, Eclipse and MySQL. Multi-tier system development using Spring, SpringBoot and Hibernate frameworks. Implemented UI using PrimeFaces, JQuery and JavaScript. Working in a team of 6 developers (leading sub-team of 2 junior programmers) designed, documented and developed current workflow software suite. Working on developing detailed documentation, UML diagrams and use-cases using Agile methodology with 3 week sprints. Currently learning AngularJS, NodeJS, Scala, Java 8 and MongoDB.

Software Engineer at the University of California, Santa Barbara.

Software Engineer

UC Santa Barbara - October 2000 to September 2009

10/00 - 09/2009

Environment: Java

Developed Billing and Accounts Receivable system(BARC), using Java, JSP and WebSphere application server. Played a major role in full software development life cycle from creating design documentation using UML to database design and code implementation. UI implementation originally started with using applets as a front end UI, but later was replaced with JSP. Back-end was implemented in Sybase and later moved to MS SQL Server. Additional financial modules (short and long term student loans) were implemented using Spring and Hibernate frameworks and JSP as a front-end. Other projects involved PHP and MySQL. Another project was a mobile applications for Android OS developed for staff of Accounting Office.

Software Engineer

Efax.com - January 1999 to July 2000

Environment: Visual C++ (Windows NT, 98), Java

Developed and debugged email-messaging software using Visual C++ (Lotus Notes API and MAPI) and Java

Software Engineer

Tecolote Research - Santa Barbara, CA - December 1997 to January 1999

Environment: Visual C++ (Windows NT), Visual Basic 5 Developed and maintained cost-estimation software for

Department of Defense in Visual C++. Created applications in Visual C++ and Visual Basic (SQL Anywhere as back-end). Major projects include enhancing existing cost estimation engine and creating GUI for the database of cost-estimation data.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science

The Johns Hopkins University - Baltimore, MD 1995 to 1997

State Electrotechnical University of St.Petersburg 1989 to 1993

SKILLS

JAVA (10+ years), MYSQL (10+ years), JSP (8 years), SYBASE (8 years), JAVASCRIPT (7 years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS

Java (10+ years)

Technical Skills

- Java (up to 1.8), C++
- HTML, JavaScript, Jquery, CSS, JSP, JSF, PrimeFaces (JSF)
- SpringBoot, Spring, Hibernate
- REST Web Services

Application Servers:

Tomcat, GlassFish3

Environments:

Windows, Mac OS X, Ubuntu

Databases: MySQL, Sybase, MongoDB